Guide to the Eugene O'Neill, Jr. Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1932-1964; Series I; 0.8; (2 boxes)
  - EUGENE O'NEILL, JR. CORRESPONDENCE
    - Kroening, Bobbie, [1950 Aug 22] (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Kropf, Ruth E., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Ladd, Don, [1949 Jun 21] (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Meyer, Elsie, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Meyer, Frank S.
      - Correspondence, 1942-47, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Correspondence, [1950 Sep 23-25] (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - The New Yorker, 1950 Feb 23 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - O'Neill, Carlotta Monterey, 1939, [1940] (Box 1, Folder 25)
      See also: "Candid Shots" album, box 9, folder 298
    - O'Neill, Eugene
      - Correspondence, 1928-29 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Correspondence, 1930-31 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Correspondence, 1932-33 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Correspondence, 1934-36 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Correspondence, 1937-38 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Correspondence, 1939-41 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Correspondence, 1942-43 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Correspondence, 1944-49 Mar (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - Correspondence, 1949 Dec 23 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Correspondence, 1950 Feb 25 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Pearson, Norman Holmes
      - Correspondence, 1939, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - Correspondence, 1947 Jul 24 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Phillips, Henry, Jr., 1941 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Pool, L., 1949 Dec 11 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Quinones-Garza, Joel, 1948 Jul 20 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Rinehart & Company, Inc., 1949 Aug 5 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      With memorandum of agreement, 1949 Jan 22.
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1948 May 11 (Box 2, Folder 43)
      Telegram.
    - Schreiber, Flora Rheta, 1950, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Towers, Bob, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 45)
      Written in blue examination book.
    - Travelers Insurance Companies, 1948 Sep 23 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      See also: Series II, Writings, "Really 'Tis Love," box 4, folder 142
    - WQXR (Radio Station: New York, N.Y.), 1950 Sep 22 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Welborne, Bill, 1949 Jan 22 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Whitney, Elise McStea, 1950, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Wilding Picture Productions, 1947 Mar 4 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - ----, George, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 51)
      With notes in Eugene O'Neill, Jr.'s hand.
    - ----, Vada, 1949 Sep 6 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - CORRESPONDENCE REGARDING EUGENE O'NEILL, JR.'S ESTATE
    - Winfield E. Aronberg
      - Frank E. Campbell, Inc., 1950 Nov 3 (Box 2, Folder 53)
      - Guaranty Trust Company of New York, 1951 Mar 16 (Box 2, Folder 54)
      - Lander, Ruth Reade, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 55)
      - Lasher, Victor N., 1950 Nov 17 (Box 2, Folder 56)
      - Meyer, Frank S., 1951 May 16 (Box 2, Folder 57)
      - New York Herald Tribune, 1950 Nov 3 (Box 2, Folder 58)
      - The New York Times, 1950 Nov 3 (Box 2, Folder 59)
      - Ogden, Alfred, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 60)
      - Palzer, Nathaniel J., 1950-51 (Box 2, Folder 61)
      - Pitt-Smith, Kathleen, 1950 Oct 13 (Box 2, Folder 62)
        Encloses letter to Carlotta Monterey O'Neill and letter from Norman Holmes Pearson.
      - Schreiber, Flora Rheta, 1950 Oct 16 (Box 2, Folder 63)
        Encloses letter to Eugene O'Neill.
    - Frank S. Meyer; Elsie Meyer
      - Bellinger, Alfred Raymond, 1950-51 (Box 2, Folder 64)
      - Bennett, C., Jr., 1950 Oct 7 (Box 2, Folder 65)
      - Bry, Lois Williams, 1950-51 (Box 2, Folder 66)
      - Burton, Barbara, 1950 Nov 22 (Box 2, Folder 67)
      - Devon, Pru, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 68)
      - Harrison, Ross, [1950 Sep 26] (Box 2, Folder 69)
      - Le Fever, Carol, [1950 Sep 27] (Box 2, Folder 70)
      - Light, James and Patti, 1950-64, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 71)
      - Mayer, Clara W., 1950 Oct 20 (Box 2, Folder 72)
      - Oates, Whitney Jennings, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 73)
      - O'Neill, Eugene, 1950-51 (Box 2, Folder 74)
      - Palzer, Nathaniel J., 1950-57 (Box 2, Folder 75-77)
        Includes Palzer's carbons to Ruth Reade Lander, Harold Lee Manierre, Floyd W. Powell, Cornelius V. V. Sewell, and Elise McStea Whitney.
      - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1950-51 (Box 2, Folder 78)
      - Pitt-Smith, Kathleen
        - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 79)
        - Correspondence, 1950-54, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 80)
          With note of explanation by Elsie Meyer.
      - Schreiber, Flora Rheta, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 81)
      - Tiffany and Company, 1950 Dec 5 (Box 2, Folder 82)
      - Tomlin, Bradley, [1950] Sep 29 (Box 2, Folder 83)
      - Weyl, Nathaniel, 1950 Oct 13 (Box 2, Folder 84)
      - Whitney, Elise McStea, [1950], n.d. (Box 2, Folder 85)
- Writings, 1923-1950; Series II; 1.2; (3 boxes)
  - ARTICLES
    - [Election of Franklin Delano Roosevelt], drafts, holograph and typescript carbon, corrected (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - "The Importance of Final Syllables in Greek Verse," article, printed version, Transactions of the American Philological Association
      - Copy 1, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 87)
        Inscribed to Norman Holmes Pearson.
      - Copy 2, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 88)
        Inscribed to Kathleen and George Pitt-Smith.
    - "The Last Name Is Not Junior," typescript carbon, corrected, [1948]
      See: Series I, Correspondence, box 1, folder 10
    - "Leap from an Ivory Tower," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 89)
      With outline, holograph.
    - "The Localization of Metrical Word-Types in the Greek Hexameter: Homer, Hesiod, and the Alexandrians," printed version, Yale Classical Studies
      - Copy 1, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 90)
      - Copy 2, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - "On Translating Homer"
      - Typescript carbon, corrected, [1950] (Box 3, Folder 92)
      - Clipping of printed version, The New Republic, 1950 Jul 17 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - "One Solid Vote for the 'Audio,'" article, clipping of printed version, [1945 Dec] (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - "Prolegomena," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - "The Prologue of the Troades of Euripides," printed version, Transactions of the American Philological Association, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - "Word-Accents and Final Syllables in Latin Verse," printed version, Transactions of the American Philological Association, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - LECTURES
    - "Antigone," holograph, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - "Aristotle, the Misunderstood Democrat," holograph (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - "Can Greek Democracy Help Us?," typescript and holograph (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - "Classical Politics I," holograph, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - "Dem[ocracy]," holograph, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - "Details," holograph, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - [The eighteenth century], holograph and typescript (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - [The eighteenth century novel], typescript, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - "Ethics, Politics, [and] the Totalitarian State," holograph and typescript (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - [Greek poetry], typescript carbon, corrected, 1942 Mar (Box 3, Folder 106)
      At Hunter College, 1942 Mar 27.
    - "The Importance of Final Syllables in Greek Verse," typescript carbon, 1939 Dec 28 (Box 3, Folder 107)
      At American Philological Association meeting, Ann Arbor (Mich.). With meeting program.
    - "Job," holograph, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - "Lib[eral] Ed[ucation]," holograph, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - "The Meanings of Aristocracy," holograph, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - [New aims and techniques in liberal education], typescript carbon (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - "On Certain Offices - Commencement Address," printed version, Connecticut College Alumnae News, 1947 Aug (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - "Oresteia," holograph, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - "Poem Analysis," holograph, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - "Pure Metrics and the Hexameter Problems," holograph, in notebook, 1935 Nov 18 (Box 3, Folder 115)
      At Classical Club, Yale University. With loose pages, holograph.
    - "Sigmund Freud; Literary Criticism; Greek Drama," typescript carbon, corrected, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 116)
      At Vassar College, 1944 Mar 23; at Wellesley College, 1944 Oct 31.
    - "The Soap Operas [and] Shakespeare," holograph (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - "Soph[ocles'] O[edipus] T[yrannus]," holograph, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - "[Sophocles'] Last Plays," holograph and typescript (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - [Teaching Greek], typescript carbon, corrected, 1944 Jan 8 (Box 3, Folder 120)
      At American Philological Association meeting, New York.
    - "Thomas Cutt's Analysis of the Hendecasyllabic," typescript carbon, corrected, 1939 Nov 6 (Box 3, Folder 121)
      At Classical Club, Yale University. With notes, holograph.
    - [The Trojan women of Euripides], holograph, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - "What's Wrong with American Education?," holograph, [1946 Oct 10] (Box 3, Folder 123)
      At Westchester Country Club. With program.
    - Fragments, holograph and typescript carbon (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - POEMS
    - "Arma Virumque," drafts, typescript, corrected and typescript carbon, 1942, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 125)
    - "A Brief Song," typescript, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 126)
    - "Commonplace Things," printed version, The Horace Mann Quarterly
      - Copy 1, 1926 Jan (Box 4, Folder 127)
        Annotated by EO, Jr. With clippings of letters to editor regarding this poem. Also includes "Dream-Things."
      - Copy 2, 1926 Jan (Box 4, Folder 128)
        With clipping of EO, Jr.'s letter to editor regarding this poem. Also includes "Dream-Things."
    - "Delirium," printed version, The Horace Mann Quarterly, 1926 Nov (Box 4, Folder 129)
    - "A Dream for a Mouse," printed version, The Horace Mann Quarterly, 1927 Feb (Box 4, Folder 130)
      Also includes "The Song of the Freight." With clipping of same.
    - "Dream-Things"
      See: "Commonplace Things," box 4, folders 127-128
    - "Earlier Thoughts," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 131)
    - "Four Poems to the Seasons," printed version, The Horace Mann Quarterly
      - Copy 1, 1926 May (Box 4, Folder 132)
      - Copy 2, 1926 May (Box 4, Folder 133)
    - "Greeked to the Squeaking Point," typescript, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 134)
    - "Later Thoughts," typescript, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 135)
    - "Lines Composed in the Erie Railroad Station, Jersey City?, Toward Midnight," drafts, holograph and typescript carbon, [1949] (Box 4, Folder 136)
    - "Marion," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 137)
    - "Media Vita," typescript, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 138)
    - "Mutatis Mutandis"
      - Draft, holograph, corrected, [1950] (Box 4, Folder 139)
      - Clipping of printed version, The New Yorker, 1950 May 20 (Box 4, Folder 139)
    - "Nausicaa," typescript, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 140)
    - "A Plea to Bear With Him," typescript, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 141)
    - "Really 'Tis Love," drafts, holograph and typescript carbon, [1949] (Box 4, Folder 142)
      Draft, holograph, written on back of letter from Travelers Insurance Companies, 1949 Nov 16.
    - "Sequelae," typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 143)
    - "Shall Neither Slumber," drafts holograph and typescript carbon (Box 4, Folder 144)
    - "Sleep," printed version, The Horace Mann Quarterly
      - Copy 1, 1924 Feb (Box 4, Folder 145)
      - Copy 2, 1924 Feb (Box 4, Folder 146)
    - "Snapshot," printed version, The Horace Mann Quarterly, 1924 Mar (Box 4, Folder 147)
    - "The Song of the Freight," poem, printed version, Helicon, 1928 Dec (Box 4, Folder 148)
      See also: "A Dream for a Mouse," box 4, folder 130
    - "This Day Our Daily," drafts, typescript, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - "Ultimum et Optimum," drafts, holograph and typescript carbon (Box 4, Folder 150)
    - Untitled poems, drafts, holograph and typescript, 1928-[50] (Box 4, Folder 151-152)
  - REVIEWS
    - "The Attic Pattern," clipping of printed version, The New York Times Book Review, 1945 Jan 28 (Box 5, Folder 153)
      Review of Paideia: The Ideals of Greek Culture by Werner Jaeger.
    - Beede, Grace Lucile. Vergil and Aratus, a Study in the Art of Translation. Review of, printed version, American Journal of Philology, [1936] (Box 5, Folder 154)
    - Fitts, Dudley and Robert Fitzgerald, trans. The Antigone of Sophocles. Review of, printed version, American Journal of Philology, 1939 Oct (Box 5, Folder 155)
    - "Homeric Hexameters," clipping of printed version, The New York Times Book Review, 1944 Nov 5 (Box 5, Folder 156)
      Review of William Benjamin Smith and Walter Miller's translation of Homer's Iliad.
    - Murray, Gilbert. Aeschylus, the Creator of Tragedy. Review of, printed version, Classical Weekly, 1941 Jan 6 (Box 5, Folder 157)
    - "Murray on the Greeks," clipping of printed version, The New York Times Book Review, 1947 May 18 (Box 5, Folder 158)
      Review of Greek Studies by Gilbert Murray.
    - Nonnos. Dionysiaca. Review of, printed version, American Journal of Philology, 1944 Jul (Box 5, Folder 159)
    - Page, Denys Lionel. Euripides. Medea. Review of, printed version, American Journal of Philology, 1939 Oct (Box 5, Folder 160)
    - "S. V. Benét's John Brown's Body "
      - Proof, corrected, [1949]
      - Clipping of printed version, The Saturday Review, 1949 Aug 6 (Box 5, Folder 161)
    - Schütze, Kurt. Beiträge zum Verständnis der Phainomena Arats. Review of, printed version, Gnomon, 1938 Mar (Box 5, Folder 162)
    - Trevelyan, H. C., trans. Euripides. Medea. Review of, printed version, Classical Weekly, 1940 Nov 18 (Box 5, Folder 163)
    - Wassermann, Jakob. Alexander in Babylon. Review of, typescript carbon, corrected (Box 5, Folder 164)
  - OTHER WRITINGS
    - "Ashes," play, printed version, The Horace Mann Quarterly, 1925 Apr (Box 5, Folder 165)
    - Bibliographical notes, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected, 1933-34, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 166)
    - "A Brief Outline of the Dido Episode," typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 167)
    - "Is This the End of the Battle?," letter to editor, printed version, The Key Reporter, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 168)
      With note by EO, Jr. on card.
    - Noyes-Cuter Prize submission, typescript carbon, corrected, 1932 Mar 27 (Box 5, Folder 169)
    - "On Wallace and a 3d Party," letter to editor, clipping of printed version, PM, 1947 Dec 28 (Box 5, Folder 170)
    - [Once upon a time...], story, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 171)
    - "Research Paper on Anacharsis," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 172)
      Annotated [by professor?].
    - "The Talmud: A Discussion on Columbia Broadcasting System's Invitation to Learning," transcript, typescript mimeograph, 1944 Dec 10 (Box 5, Folder 173)
      EO, Jr. as Chairman.
    - "Victory," story, printed version, The Horace Mann Quarterly, 1923 Nov (Box 5, Folder 174)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS
    - Cutt, Thomas. "Meter and Diction in Catullus' Hendecasyllabic," dissertation, printed version, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 175)
      Inscribed to EO, Jr.
    - Furness, Clifton Joseph. "The Barbarous Barber Emperor: A Melodrama-Burlesque on the Character of the Russian Tsar Peter the Great," typescript carbon, corrected, in volume, 1923 Aug (Box 5, Folder 176)
      With note of explanation by Norman Holmes Pearson.
    - The Horace Mann Quarterly, 1925, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 177)
- Personal Papers, 1912-1950; Series III; 0.4; (1 box)
  Series III, Personal Papers, is organized into three subseries: Legal Materials, University Study and Teaching, and Other. Each subseries is arranged alphabetically.
  - LEGAL MATERIALS
    - Document regarding Eugene O'Neill's divorce from Kathleen Pitt-Smith, typescript carbon, 1912 Jun (Box 6, Folder 178)
    - Lease with Harold Lee Manierre for house in Woodstock, N.Y., 1948 Apr 10 (Box 6, Folder 179)
    - Passport, 1932 Jun 22
      See: Series IV, Photographs, box 7, folder 219
    - Receipts for bank loans, 1947-49 (Box 6, Folder 180)
      Receipts dated 1947 Mar 4 and 1949 Mar 4 signed by Eugene O'Neill; receipt dated 1949 Dec 9 signed by Frank S. Meyer.
    - Will, 1947 Mar 17 (Box 6, Folder 181)
  - UNIVERSITY STUDY AND TEACHING
    - Course syllabi, typescript mimeograph, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 182)
    - Examinations, 1935-36 (Box 6, Folder 183)
    - Universität Freiburg im Breisgau. Materials relating to study, 1932-33 (Box 6, Folder 184)
      Includes acceptance letter, course cards, matriculation fee card, course catalog, grade report, identity card, and notes.
    - Yale University
      - Commencement programs, 1932, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 185)
      - Grades for graduate study, 1942 Aug 31 (Box 6, Folder 186)
      - Grades for undergraduate study, 1942 Aug 31
      - Jacob Cooper Prize. Certificate of award, 1932 Jun 13 (Box 6, Folder 187)
      - Noyes-Cutter Prize. Certificate of award, 1932 May 11 (Box 6, Folder 188)
      - Soldiers Memorial Foote Fellowship. Certificates of award (four), 1932-35 (Box 6, Folder 189)
  - OTHER
    - Address book, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 190)
    - Autobiographical notes, holograph and typescript (Box 6, Folder 191)
    - Birth certificate (two photostats), 1931, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 192)
    - Business card, [194-] (Box 6, Folder 193)
    - Clippings about Eugene O'Neill, Jr., 1945-50, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 194-195)
    - Clippings. General, 1947, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 196)
    - Empty envelopes, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 197-198)
      Some annotated by EO, Jr.; some stored photographs.
    - Inscriptions by Eugene O'Neill to Eugene O'Neill, Jr., typescript, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 199)
      Probably typed by Elsie Meyer from EO, Jr.'s copies of EO's plays.
    - List made by Frank S. Meyer of people who received items from estate of Eugene O'Neill, Jr., [1950] (Box 6, Folder 200)
    - Pardee Morris House (New Haven, Conn.). Materials relating to, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 201)
    - Personal notes, holograph and typescript mimeograph (Box 6, Folder 202)
    - Program for performance in "New Horizons" in The Night of Knights, 1946 May 22 (Box 6, Folder 203)
    - Scrapbook of clippings and photographs, 1945-46
    - Wallet, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 204)
      With: business card; social security card; four draft registration cards; Actors' Equity Association, American Federation of Radio Artists, and United Steelworkers of America membership cards; car insurance card; vehicle registration; two car ownership cards; and two notes.
    - Young Men's Christian Associations. International Committee. Certificate for Honorable Mention in Radio Script Contest for "Choice for North America", n.d.
- Photographs, 1862-1947; Series IV; 0.8; (2 boxes)
  Series IV, Photographs, is organized into five subseries: Family, Other People, Places, Albums, and Other. Each subseries is arranged alphabetically and then chronologically.
  - FAMILY
    - Camblas, Henry S. Standing carrying sword and smoking pipe, 1862 Sep (Box 7, Folder 205)
      Grandfather of Kathleen Pitt-Smith.
    - [Greene, Mary Elizabeth]
      - Sitting in window in Germany, reading, [1932?] (Box 7, Folder 206)
      - Standing in street, in Germany, wearing fur-trimmed coat, [1932?] (Box 7, Folder 207)
      - Riding bicycle, in Germany (copy print), [1932?] (Box 7, Folder 208)
      - Standing outside next to dog, [193-?] (Box 7, Folder 209)
    - [Jenkins, Kate Camblas?]
      - Sitting on couch, smoking (3 versions), [192-?] (Box 7, Folder 210)
      - Sitting on dock, knitting, [193-?] (Box 7, Folder 211)
        In unidentified hand on back: "Nana."
    - O'Neill, Carlotta Monterey. Studio portrait, close-up, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 212)
      Inscribed by CMO to EO, Jr., 1929 Aug.
    - O'Neill, Eugene
      - Studio portrait by Nickolas Muray, 1922 (Box 7, Folder 213)
        Inscribed by EO to EO, Jr., 1922 May 17.
      - Studio portrait by Ben Pinchot, close-up, looking at camera, [1927] (Box 7, Folder 214)
        Inscribed by EO to EO, Jr.
      - Photograph of drawing by Mai-Mai Sze of Eugene O'Neill (copy), [1945] (Box 7, Folder 215)
    - O'Neill, Eugene, Jr.
      - Standing on beach [in Provincetown, Mass.?] holding bags, [1922?] (Box 7, Folder 216)
      - Wearing bathing suit, sitting in rowboat, [192-?] (Box 7, Folder 217)
      - Wearing bathing suit, standing with fox terrier dog at Château du Plessis (St. Antoine-du-Rocher, Indre et Loire, France), [1929] (Box 7, Folder 218)
        Annotated on back by EO, Jr.
      - Passport, 1932 Jun 22 (Box 7, Folder 219)
        Includes photograph (crossed out) of Mary Elizabeth Greene.
      - Portrait, looking at camera, [1932] (Box 7, Folder 220)
      - Standing outside next to steps in Germany, [1932?] (Box 7, Folder 221)
      - Sitting in window in Germany, reading and smoking, [1932?] (Box 7, Folder 222)
      - Standing outside, holding glass of beer, in Germany (copy print), [1932?] (Box 7, Folder 223)
      - Standing in street, in Germany (copy print), [1932?] (Box 7, Folder 224)
      - Sitting on deck chair on boat, holding glass of beer (copy print), [1932?] (Box 7, Folder 225)
      - Standing outside on lawn, [193-] (Box 7, Folder 226)
      - Portrait, facing to right, looking at camera, [193-] (Box 7, Folder 227)
      - Standing with N. William Bry and unidentified man at ranch, [193-] (Box 7, Folder 228)
      - Standing with group of people at ranch, [193-] (Box 7, Folder 229)
      - Portrait by Carl Van Vechten, standing in front of doorway, [1937] (Box 7, Folder 230)
        Inscribed by EO, Jr. to Lois Williams Bry in Greek. With note of explanation from Max Kahn to David Strauss.
      - Sitting on rock with Mary Elizabeth Greene, [193-] (Box 7, Folder 231)
      - Sitting in boat with two unidentified men (Box 7, Folder 232)
      - Riding horse at Lois Williams Bry's ranch in Ennis (Mont.) (copy print), [1939] (Box 7, Folder 233)
      - Cutting wood with Sally O'Neill, [194-?] (Box 7, Folder 234)
      - Sitting on lawn chair at Pardee Morris House (New Haven, Conn.) (copy print), [194-?] (Box 7, Folder 235)
      - Standing in front of Pardee Morris House (New Haven, Conn.) next to Marjorie F. Hayward sitting on lawn chair (copy print), [194-?] (Box 7, Folder 235)
      - Portrait in pin-striped suit (2 versions), [1943] (Box 7, Folder 236)
      - Group portrait at table at Berkowitz's Roumanian Restaurant (New York, N.Y.), [194-] (Box 7, Folder 237)
        In souvenir enclosure, inscribed (some in Hebrew) by people in portrait.
      - Group portrait at table at Joe's Roumanian Tavern (New York, N.Y.), [194-] (Box 7, Folder 238)
      - Sitting at table with two unidentified men, for CBS broadcast, [194-] (Box 7, Folder 239)
      - Sitting at table with two unidentified men sitting and one unidentified man standing, for CBS broadcast, [194-] (Box 7, Folder 239)
      - Sitting at table with two unidentified men for broadcast (3 versions), [194-] (Box 7, Folder 240)
      - Standing, reading into microphone for ABC broadcast, [194-] (Box 7, Folder 241)
      - Scrapbook of clippings and photographs, 1945-46
        See: Series III, Personal Papers, box 13, folder 302
      - Group portrait of cast of "The Life of Mother Alphonsa" on WNEW-TV (New York, N.Y.), [1946 Jun] (Box 7, Folder 242)
        Seated, left to right: Abby Lewis, EO, Jr., Elissa Landi, Barry Thomson, Eda Reiss Merin. Standing: John Grogan, Paul Conrad, Shepard Menken, Richard Leone, Peg Hillias, Somer Alberg, Thomas Heaphy, Harriet Priestley, Rusty Lane, and Kay Reed.
      - Sitting on bench, lighting cigarette, [1947] (Box 7, Folder 243)
        Stamped "Grossinger's 1947."
      - Standing in front of bench, [1947] (Box 7, Folder 244)
      - Standing with unidentified man, [1947] (Box 7, Folder 244)
      - Sitting on bench with two unidentified men, [1947] (Box 7, Folder 244)
      - Sitting on bench with two unidentified men and one unidentified woman (2 versions), [1947] (Box 7, Folder 244)